



Leo Hajder

O Home: Put Supavla 28, 21000, Split, Croatia

Email: leohajder@gmail.com **Phone:** (+385) 918977786

Website: https://leohajder.github.io

Website: https://www.linkedin.com/in/leohajder

Website: https://github.com/leohajder

Gender: Male **Date of birth:** 14/11/1987 **Nationality:** Croatian

ABOUT ME

I am a software developer mostly based in PHP and the Symfony framework. I also have a good working knowledge of Sylius, Ibexa CMS, and currently gaining more experience with API Platform. I am also capable of performing basic to intermediate tasks with JavaScript and CSS.

I have about eight years of professional experience in working on several projects of varying size, age and condition while collaborating with people from all departments, including direct communication with clients and product owners.

I enjoy building new solutions and integrating systems via APIs while using current best practices and writing clean code. I like to optimize early enough to make the code faster and more readable, but not too soon to lose perspective of the issue at hand or overengineer the solution.

I can work in a team and by myself, share my knowledge and mentor my coworkers, and I am always open to give and receive constructive feedback and improve myself and the team as a whole. Taking pride in my work and making my team proud is crucial to me.

I would describe myself as open to all people and experiences. It is never a bad idea to learn something new. You may find me funny sometimes, and I believe any day is better if you find something to smile about.

WORK EXPERIENCE

[10/02/2020 - Current] Backend Developer

Netgen https://netgen.io/

Address: Savska cesta 182, 10000, Zagreb, Croatia

- developing and maintaining proprietary code for clients
- making open source contributions via the Netgen stack
- coding in PHP/Symfony/Ibexa/Sylius

[01/04/2019 - 07/02/2020] **Backend Developer**

MojPosao (Tau On-Line d.o.o.) https://mojposao.hr/

Address: Strojarska cesta 20, 10000, Zagreb, Croatia

- developing and maintaining code for in-house projects
- coding in PHP/Symfony, JavaScript/TypeScript/Node.js/Nest.js and Python/Django
- · architectural design and development of a new multisite backend API as co-tech lead
- gaining basic experience in AWS and serverless platforms

[01/09/2017 – 31/03/2019] **Junior Developer**

MojPosao (Tau On-Line d.o.o.) https://mojposao.hr/

Address: Strojarska cesta 20, 10000, Zagreb, Croatia

- developing and maintaining code for in-house projects
- coding in PHP, mostly in Symfony
- integrating external services and APIs
- · architectural design, development, maintenance and management of most aspects of the application and the project of MojPosao Viber and Facebook chatbots as the only developer and tech lead

[01/11/2016 - 31/05/2017] **Junior Backend Developer**

Human https://www.humaninteraction.com/

Address: Rusanova 13, 10000, Zagreb, Croatia

- developing and maintaining code for commercial and in-house projects
- working on websites and e-commerce web applications
- coding in PHP, mostly in Symfony and Sylius

EDUCATION AND TRAIN-ING

[01/09/2003 - 30/06/2007] Highschool graduate

3. gimnazija

City: Split | Country: Croatia |

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Croatian

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Proficient English

I am proficient in English in speaking and writing, using adequate register and degree of formality to suit all scenarios of communication with coworkers, clients and other personnel in the business context. Thus I am able to discuss all phases of software development regarding technical details, task administration, code analysis, extracting crucial information from the clients to ensure optimal understanding of features and issues, providing accurate feedback, and anything else I might come across in a working environment.

Please find the attached statement of result of a CAE test taken in 2007. However, my working knowledge has significantly improved since then.

Link: https://leohajder.github.io/docs/cae_statement_of_result.pdf

Ability to work in a team and by myself

I consider myself capable of performing an array of tasks both as a member of a team and by myself. I approach my work with great responsibility and care for the quality of the end product.

I believe I will display adequate levels of professionalism and expertise while performing my tasks, discussing ideas for solutions, giving and receiving feedback, etc. Also, I strongly believe that any potential issues, roadblocks, unforeseen circumstances and such should be communicated as early as possible, to find the best way to address them and continue working smoothly.

Willingness to fit in

I always do my best to help my coworkers and the company as a whole, present them in a positive light, conduct myself professionally and look to bring cohesion to the team in all situations.

MANAGEMENT AND LEADERSHIP SKILLS

Mentoring students and interns

At my current company I was given an opportunity to mentor and supervise a group of internship students while working on a project which will be used internally to create and organize a digital knowledge base by uploading videos of knowledge sharing sessions, assigning tags and categories, dividing into chapters, transcribing, translating the transcripts, etc.

I held daily standup meetings, helped guide brainstorming sessions, discussions about solutions and personal performance reviews. I also provided code analysis and tried my best to give detailed explanations for all change requests, while enforcing the best practices regarding clean code.

I am proud to say the company has decided to offer all the interns part time work-andstudy contracts, and I would like to think that my guidance has helped them in that achievement. I would gladly participate in such activities again if an opportunity presents itself.

ORGANISATIONAL SKILLS

Assisting in conference organization

My current company being the main driving force behind Web Summer Camp, I am always happy to help organize, facilitate and run the events. This includes working on the registration desk, helping with equipment setup, providing information to speakers and attendees, running errands.

Link: https://websummercamp.com/

DIGITAL SKILLS

My Digital Skills

PHP | Symfony | Ibexa | Sylius | JavaScript | MySQL | PostgreSQL | MongoDB | DoctrineORM

DRIVING LICENCE

Motorbikes: AM

Cars: B

[01/03/2007] **CAE certificate Awarding institution:** University of Cambridge, ESOL Examinations **Link:** https://leohajder.github.io/docs/cae statement of result.pdf